He's fast!
他好快
Faster than anyone I've ever fought before.
他比我之前遇過的任何對手都要快
And that sword...
還有那把劍...
He uses the curve on the blade
他會視攻擊範圍的不同
to make up for the difference in reach.
靈活運用彎曲的劍身
You've got to be kidding me. He's unarmed!
這是在跟我開什麼玩笑? 他是赤手空拳耶
I'm a warrior from Miklagard, for crying out loud.
我可是來自於米克拉迦德的戰士
"I have never once been glad," was it?
“我從來沒感到開心過”,是嗎?
Jeez...
天啊
What kind of monsters was he surrounded by?
他身邊圍繞著一群什麼樣的怪物啊?
I'll keep hammering him.
我會繼續追擊他
You can't hit me!
你打不到我
- He's strong.
-他好強
Why is such a skilled fighter working as a bodyguard on a farm?
為什麼這麼厲害的打手 會在農場當守衛?
How did a man like him become a slave?
像他這樣的人怎麼會變成奴隸?
No, I need to calm down. I can't let him set the pace.
不行,我得冷靜,我不能讓他佔上風
All I need to do...
我只需要...
He can move even faster?
他還能更快?
I can see it.
我看到了
He got me.
他逮到我了
Gardar is...
哥達他...
- Snake! - Don't do it, Snake!
-蛇... -別這樣,蛇!
Don't kill...
別殺了...
Gardar.
哥達
Please...
求求你
let him go.
放了他
Get your head out of the clouds, Arnheid.
阿奴納,妳給我清醒點
He killed five of my subordinates.
他殺了我五名手下
There's no way I can forgive him.
我絕不可能放過他
Snake! I will do everything that I can to honor the deaths of your subordinates.
蛇,我會盡一切力量 補償你死去的手下
- Even if that means selling my fields-- - Shut up, Gramps!
-即使我需要賣了我的農地... -閉嘴,老頭子!
It's not about the money.
不是錢的問題
It's true that my subordinates and I are all
我和我的手下的確全都是
stupid, good-for-nothing, small-time crooks.
愚蠢且一無是處的小混混
We're vagabonds who can't even use our real names because of past offenses.
我們因為過去的罪過 現在成了必須隱姓埋名的流浪漢
Is that why you don't care even if they die?
所以我們的死活 對你來說根本不重要,對嗎?
Is Gardar's life worth that much?
哥達的性命這麼有價值嗎?
Is it worth more than five of my subordinates?
比五名手下的性命還有價值嗎?
Tell me, Thorfinn and Arnheid,
托爾芬、阿奴納,告訴我
the difference in their worth.
他們之間的差別有多大?
That means there is no difference.
這就表示他們之間沒有差別
- Well then... - No!
-那好... -不要
I will have him pay
我會要他...
a life for a life!
...一命還一命!
Are you still going to fight?
你打算繼續打下去嗎?
Will you get revenge
你會替哥達
for Gardar?
復仇嗎?
You're the one who cut Gardar's rope, right Arnheid?
是妳切斷了哥達的繩索 對吧,阿奴納?
You guys will be punished for what you did.
你們會因你們的所作所為受到懲罰
I'll tie you up until the master returns--
我會把你們綁起來 直到主人回來為止
That's enough! Gardar!
夠了,哥達
If you keep that up he'll die!
如果你不放手,他會死
Gardar!
哥達
Damn it! How strong is he?
該死,他怎麼這麼強壯?
Let go!
放手
Gardar!
哥達
Let's go back, Gardar.
我們回去吧,哥達
It's all right now.
現在沒事了
No one is trying to get in our way anymore.
再也沒有任何人能夠阻擋我們
Hjalti is waiting for us too.
賈赫提也在等著我們
Hjalti...
賈赫提...
Where
他現在...
is he now?
在哪裡?
Your older brother is looking after him in Birka.
你哥哥在比爾卡照顧著他
I had him take refuge there before the war began.
我在戰爭爆發前就把他送過去避難了
I see.
是喔
My older brother is always taking care of me.
我哥哥總是很照顧我
When we go to pick up Hjalti,
我們去接賈赫提的時候
I have to take a thank you gift.
得帶上一份謝禮
- Excuse me, you there. - Huh?
-這位仁兄,不好意思 -怎麼了?
Is this wagon yours?
這輛馬車是你的嗎?
I would like to borrow it.
方便借給我嗎?
- No... - It's mine.
-不是... -是我的
I'll give it to you,
我把馬車送給你
Gardar.
哥達
Pardon me for speaking to you from up here.
不好意思,我得在車上跟您說話
What is your name, sir?
請問您的大名是?
I'm Sverkel.
我叫斯威克
Go on, back to your home.
去吧,回家吧
Thank you, Sverkel.
謝謝你,斯威克
Thorfinn...
托爾芬
Words cannot express my gratitude for you and Einar.
任何言語都無法表達 我對你和埃納爾的謝意
This is reckless, Arnheid.
這太莽撞了,阿奴納
Gardar isn't going to...
哥達他沒辦法...
It's fine.
沒關係
Please send us off.
請跟我們道別吧
It's cold.
好冷
I'm frozen to the core.
冷到骨子裡了
How pitiful...
真可憐
Such unfortunate beings who were
這些不幸的人
abandoned by the gods.
被上帝遺棄
You are...
你是...
You are my new pride and joy.
你是我新的驕傲和喜悅
Hjalti! Hjalti, son of Gardar!
賈赫提...哥達的兒子
I will continue fighting...
我會持續努力
so you can take pride in my honor
讓你能夠以我為榮
and so we can become wealthy someday.
我們總有一天會成為富人
One second!
等等
What is it?
怎麼了嗎?
For honor
為了榮耀
and wealth.
和財富
Gardar?
哥達?
How old
賈赫提...
is Hjalti now?
現在多大了?
Eight?
八歲了嗎?
Nine?
還是九歲?
He's six.
是六歲
My goodness...
我的天
I've lost track of time ever since I became a slave.
我自從成了奴隸之後 就沒有時間概念了
Six, huh? I see...
六歲?是喔...
That's too bad.
太可惜了
I couldn't see him at his most adorable age.
我錯過了他最討人喜歡的年紀
He was still one when I parted with him.
我跟他分開的時候,他才一歲
Man...
天啊
He has probably long forgotten about us.
他可能早就忘了我們兩個了
Considering the fact that he's my child, I bet he's causing quite the mischief.
既然他是我的兒子 我打包票他一定相當調皮
Like setting fire to the horse's tail.
像是會在馬尾巴上點火
You did such a thing when you were a child?
你小時候做過這種事?
Yeah. My father got so mad at me.
對呀,我爸超生氣的
When he becomes old enough,
等他再大一點
he'll probably say that he wants to become a Viking.
他可能會說想要當個維京人
Like all boys do.
就跟所有的男孩一樣
But I will not allow that.
但我不會允許他這麼做
Gardar!
哥達!
It's okay.
沒事的
I'm a little tired, that's all.
我只是有點累,沒什麼
Just let me rest.
讓我休息一下就好
You're sure about this?
你們確定要這麼做嗎?
Yeah. We've made up our minds.
對,我們下定決心了
If we get the iron, we'll be able to live comfortably.
如果我們得到鐵礦 就能舒舒服服地過日子了
Your family too.
你的家人也是
- Okay. I'll go too. - All right!
-好,我也會加入 -太好了
Everyone's gathered at the village square.
大家會在村裡的廣場集合
Come on, let's hurry.
來吧,我們快點過去
Arnheid...
阿奴納
Hjalti...
賈赫提
I will never
我再也不會
leave you two alone
棄你們兩個於...
again...
不顧了
I'm... home...
我回來了
Welcome home...
你到家了
Gardar.
哥達
"First Course of Action."
最初的手段
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯:歐德慧